好了 提摩西
All right, Timothy.
好戲上場了 兄弟
It is go time, brother. Okay?
我需要五分鐘後上樓
Now, I need to be upstairs in five--
改成三分鐘
make that three-minutes...
不好意思 這該死的芯片
I'm sorry, it's this darn chip.
不知道是要刷一下
I don't know whether to-to swipe it
碰一下 還是感應一下 所以
or tap it or wave it. Which means I need to know
我需要知道你們願意支付的上限
the ceiling, okay? The absolute ceiling that
最高的價格
your guys are willing to pay.
不好意思 這樣吧
Sorry. You know what?
我付現金
I'll just get cash.
她的賬我結 給我來個美式中杯
Um, hers is on me. I'll take a tall drip,
零錢不用找了 23 好的
and you can keep the change. 23, great.
那我要在19成交
Which means I'm gonna close at 19,
等他們準備跳單時 你記得提醒你老闆
so you remind your bosses how much I saved them
我幫他們節省了多少錢
when they try to fight my bill.
今天真是一個美好的開始
Well, isn't that a nice way to start the day?
別人還說這世界要完蛋了
And they say the world is going to poop.
天哪
Oh, dear.
我幫你
I got you.
今天的好心人真多
Oh. Well, this is the day of kind gestures.
感激不盡
I can't thank you enough.
我送你一個
May I offer you one?
我奶奶超喜歡這些
Oh. My grandma loves these.
這是生物本能
It's biological.
到了一定年紀 我們就開始買這些
We hit a certain age and we start buying 'em.
相信我 我也想拒絕的
Believe you me, I tried to resist,
可是到了65以後 不知不覺地
and then I turned 65, and next thing I know,
就發現自己站在好多超市裏
I'm standing smack-dab in the middle of a Costco
拿著個四磅重的袋子
with a four-pound bag.
21樓 謝謝
Uh, 21st floor, please.
可能就是這樣
I guess that's the thing.
一生中很多時刻 我們都成了
Lots of times in life, we become exactly who
別人期望我們成為的樣子
people expect us to be.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
拜
Bye.
克裏斯汀 幫我開下門 我沒手開
Kristine, can you buzz me in? Hands are full.
你好 週一快樂
Hello and happy Monday.
開始之前
Before we dive in,
向你們這些大都會球迷 致以深切哀悼
my deep condolences to all you Mets fans.
好吧 那真是
All right, that's... yes.
對 我聽說你們很多人去看了比賽
Yeah, I heard a bunch of you went to the game.
團建 為了團隊氣氛
Team building. It's good for morale.
向大家表明 即使我現在成了權益合夥人
Shows that even though I'm an equity partner now,
我還是跟你們一樣
I am still one of you,
打心眼兒裏是個普通合夥人
a regular partner at heart,
不談薪水的話
if not in salary.
好了
Here we go.
奧林匹亞 我聽說哈里斯的民事訴訟
Olympia, I heard you got a $2 million offer
你拿到了200萬的和解報價
to settle the Harris civil action.
是的 我拒絕了 庭審定在
Yes, and I rejected it. That trial is slated to start
明天 無論如何 都不能進入庭審
tomorrow, and you cannot go to trial under any circumstance.
我會達成交易的
And I will be closing,
可是兩百萬遠遠不夠 伊利亞
but $2 million is not enough, Elijah.
雷蒙德·哈里斯失去了26年的時光
Raymond Harris lost 26 years of his life.
我覺得最少得四百萬
I need $4 million, minimum.
如果我能找到確鑿證據
20 if I can just find the smoking gun
證明警察腐敗 那就得要兩千萬
to prove that there was police corruption.
你都找了六個月了
You've been looking for six months.
沒有給我分配合適的資源
Well, I haven't been allocated the proper resources,
朱利安 給你配了兩個
Julian. You have two associates
初級律師 24小時任你差遭
working around the clock.
兩個初級律師 抵不上一個普通律師
Two very junior associates who equal one mediocre associate.
你就是這麼鼓舞士氣的
Is that your way of building morale?
聽著 我可能有了新線索
Look, I might have a new lead.
那個妓女的素描
A sketch of the prostitute...
結束了 奧林匹亞
It's over, Olympia,
結了這個案子
close the case.
朱利安
Julian,
說說皮搏迪的情況
talk to me about Peabody.
我們昨晚私下聊了
We back-channeled last night,
他們把價格提到一千九百萬
and I got them up to $19 million.
實際上 你們可以從
Actually, you can get
皮博迪那裏要到更多
quite a bit more out of Peabody.
你哪位
Uh, who are you?
不好意思 我有點激動得忘乎所以了
Sorry, I got a little ahead of myself in my excitement.
非正式場合 叫我瑪蒂
I'm Matty, informally.
正式場合叫我瑪德琳·馬特洛克
Formally Madeline Matlock.
對 跟之前電視劇裏的馬特洛克同名
Yes, Matlock like the old TV show,
1984年到1992年期間 聽到的全是這個
which was all I heard between 1984 and 1992.
你跟馬特洛克一樣是個律師 你跟馬特洛克一樣是個律師
"You're a lawyer like Matlock. You're a lawyer like Matlock."
每次我都要糾正他們
And every time I'd correct 'em,
不對 他是假律師
"No, he's just pretending.
我可是真律師
You know, I'm a real lawyer."
可是你們懂的 抗議次數多了
But, you know, you can only protest so much
別人就會覺得你小題大做 心胸狹隘
before you sound like you got a big old pole up your heinie,
聽以 我也就不糾結了
so I just let 'em have it
只是回答 對 對 對
and I just said, "Yeah, well, yeah,
我跟馬特洛克一樣 是律師
I'm a lawyer just like Matlock."
您在哪家律所工作
A lawyer working for...
希望是在這裏
You, hopefully.
你們要招初級律師
You have an associate position open,
要想找個面試機會真難得
and it's been really hard to get an interview.
我差點以為是因為我太老了
And I almost think it's 'cause of my age,
但是 這樣就違背了反歧視規定
but that'd be violating discriminatory protections.
關鍵是 我必須想辦法
The point is, I just had to figure out
打破這種困境
a way to break through the noise.
你的確為自己贏得了面試機會
I think you definitely earned yourself an interview.
感謝您的認可
Well, thank you for that,
可我要的不是面試
but I don't want an interview.
而是工作
I want a job.
提醒一下
And as a reminder,
我很清楚皮博迪願意
I do know the number that Peabody
支付和解金
is willing to pay,
而且比一千九百萬高一點兒
and it is significantly higher than $19 million.
當然 也不能對皮博迪漫天要價
Course, I wouldn't overplay my hand with Peabody either.
我一向認為 談判既是一門藝術
I always say negotiations are an art
也是一個陷阱
and a trap.
那就避開陷阱 你怎麼知道報價的
Let's avoid traps, then. How do you know the number?
你看女人到了我這個年紀
Well, you see, there's this funny thing
就有一個有趣的現象
that happens when women age.
好像沒人會注意到我們
We become damn near invisible.
我不是在抱怨
Oh, not that I'm complaining.
我也有過高光時刻
I had my moment in the sun.
再說了 無人警惕是致勝的法寶
Plus it's useful because nobody sees us coming.
我就是這樣騙過你們保安的
That's how I got through your security.
好幾次了
Several times.
我也是這樣知道
And it's also how I knew that
皮博迪的律師 在8點15到25之間
Peabody's counsel grabs coffee
買咖啡時 向他的客戶匯報情況的
and updates his client between 8:15 and 8:25.
對方給價多少
What's the number?
我被錄用了嗎
Am I hired?
所有人錄用前 都有兩周的試用期
No one is hired without a two-week trial.
他們的上限是多少
What's their ceiling?
兩千三百萬
$23 million.
意思是我剛剛替你們
Which means I just made you
賺了四百萬
$4 million.
還需要我試用兩周嗎
Do I still need a two-week trial?
是的
Yes.
那好吧 我就從今天開始
All right, fine. I'll start today.
說說看 馬特洛克女士
Tell me, Ms. Matlock,
為什麼想在我們律所工作
why do you want to work at my firm?
人生中總有些時候
There's a time in life when you make decisions
是基於自己的對錯觀做決定
based on what you think is right,
也有一些時候 基於自己的經濟狀況做決定
and there's a time when you make decisions based on money.
我一輩子都是基於我認為的正確做事
I did what was right all my life, and now
現在我就想多掙錢
I need to make it rain,
給我派個案子
so point me to a case
讓我工作吧
and put me to work.
她確實要求加派人手
She did ask for extra resources.
我們結識的時機好像不太好
We seem to have gotten off on the wrong foot.
這走得也太快了
Wow, that is quite the pace.
我只想真正派上用場
Um, I just truly want to be useful.
無論你需要什麼 能力
Anything you need. Competence.
我需要基本的能力
I need basic competence.
你上一次從事法律工作是什麼時候
When was the last time you practiced law?
那是1991年
Um, well, that was in 1991.
我知道 時隔30年肯定有困難
And I understand 30 years can seem challenging,
但是我向你保證 我基本上時時關注
but I assure you, I have remained pretty...
法律進展
nearly up to date.
基本上 還是差不多
"Pretty nearly" or "almost sorta"?
讓我向你證明
Just let me prove that
告訴我 要怎麼做
I can be useful. Tell me how to do that.
那就在感恩節幫幫我吧
Get me all of Thanksgiving.
不好意思 我沒聽懂
I'm sorry, I'm not following.
我一小時收費一千二 去找一個
I charge $1,200 an hour, so clear that up
你負擔得起的人 給你解釋吧
with somebody whose time you can afford.
你們倆有消息嗎 還 沒有
You two, anything? Nothing, no, not yet.
記得我說過的嗎 回答不要這麼囉嗦
Remember what we talked about? That should have been one word.
好了 電話隨時可能進來
Now, the call's coming in any minute.
去會議室見我
Meet me in the conference room
帶上這位新律師
and bring the new lawyer with you.
瑪德琳·馬特洛克
Madeline Matlock.
跟那個電視節目同名
Like the TV show.
什麼節目
What TV show?
沒錯 你們可以叫我瑪蒂
Exactly. You can call me Matty.
第一天上班
First day on the job,
好激動加入這個團隊
thrilled to be part of the team.
不要 這等於是噩夢
Oh, no. This is gonna be a nightmare.
友善點 友善
Be nice. Nice?
別叫我友善 我需要資深合夥人的培訓
Don't tell me to be nice. I need to be trained by
不是資深老年人
senior partners, not senior citizens.
天哪 無意冒犯 佩利·梅森
Oh, God. No offense, Perry Mason.
是馬特洛克 就算你說無意冒犯
Ha, Matlock. You know, if you say "no offense,"
不代表這就有禮貌了 我們被降到
it doesn't make it any less rude. We just got demoted
第三檔了 比利
to a third, Billy.
替莎拉說句話
In Sarah's defense, um,
她就是脾氣暴躁
she's a raging bitch.
她怎麼這麼火爆
Why is she so pissy?
沒有私生活
No social life.
再加上她野心勃勃
And plus she's wildly ambitious,
我們在這個案子上 花費了六個月時間
and we've been working on this case for six months now,
而奧林匹亞還是不知道我們倆的名字 她只說 你們倆
and Olympia still calls us "youtwo." One word.
所以 你加入的不算是什麼精英團隊
So, yeah, you're not exactly joining the A-team.
又是個你沒聽說過的電視節目名稱
Another old TV show you never heard of?
我和祖母看過那些電視劇
Well, my abuela and I watched telenovelas.
你知道那些劇嗎 不知道
You know any of those? No.
也正常
That's fair.
趁我還沒忘
Hey, before I forget,
奧林匹亞說要我給她感恩節
Olympia mentioned I should get her Thanksgiving.
你聽明白她什麼意思嗎
You any idea what she's talking about?
她可能是指監護權
Uh, probably a custody thing.
聽說他們的離婚已經鐵板釘釘
Word is, their divorce is almost finalized.
對了 頂級零食點在這裏
FYI, top snack destination here.
咸味甜味全都有
You've got salty, you've got sweet,
要是你想哭 後面還有天井
you've got access to the back patio in case you need to cry.
申明一下 我想吃咸的
Well, for the record, I'm salty.
希望我不至於哭吧
I'm hoping I won't cry.
你剛才說他們的離婚
You said "their divorce."
奧林匹亞跟誰離婚
Who's Olympia divorcing?
朱利安
Julian.
跟她吵架的那位
Oh, the guy she was arguing with.
把它歸為 我永遠不會摻和的事
Well, file that under "Things I'm never gonna
絕對 不可能 永遠 不會
get involved with, no way, nohow, no, sirree, Bob."
我要用老辦法贏得她的信任
I'm gonna win her over the old-fashioned way.
跟我說說案情吧
Catch me up on the case.
好 雷蒙德·哈里斯因多起謀殺強姦罪
Yep. Raymond Harris spent 26 years in jail
判刑入獄26年
as a convicted serial murderer/rapist
可是最近的DNA證據 洗清了他的罪名
but was recently exonerated through DNA evidence.
那時候的警局 水渾得不行
Now, the police department was definitely dirty back then,
各種不當行為 但是
tons of misconduct, but
想要給他爭取到應得的賠償
in order to get the payout that he deserves,
我們必須找到確鑿的證據
we-we need to find the smoking gun.
為什麼大家覺得一定能找到呢
Why is everybody so sure there is one?
因為我們一個線人從他已故的
Well, because we got a tip from a guy who got a tip
退休跟警察叔叔那裏 得到了線報
from his dead uncle who was a retired cop.
天啊 是的
Oh, Lord. Yeah.
總之 在雷蒙德被拘期間
Anyway, apparently a prostitute escaped
有個妓女又遭遇了類似襲擊 長襪被纏在脖子上
a really similar attack while Raymond was still in custody.
完全遵循之前的模式 但她逃了出來
Stocking around the neck, the whole nine.
據說 她去警局報案了
Word is, she went down to the station to file a report,
只不過沒記錄
only there's no record of it,
也就是說 如果真有 也被掩蓋了
which means if it exists, it was buried.
我猜你應該找不到26年前
Well, I'm guessing you can't find the prostitute
那個妓女了
from 26 years ago.
連她名字都不知道
Don't know her name,
是生是死 就更不知情了
much less if she's alive.
這世界上可是有很多隱形人的
Well, there's a lot of invisible people in the world.
在合夥人會議上
In the partners' meeting,
奧林匹亞提到過素描
Olympia said something about a sketch?
這很複雜
Well, that's complicated.
但抱歉問一下
Uh, I'm sorry.
你是怎麼加入合夥人會議的
How-how did you get into the partners' meeting?
這說來話長了
Oh, that's a long story.
下次我們一起吃咸的 我再告訴你
I'll tell you about it next time we share something salty.
還有其他信息要告訴我嗎
Is there anything else
能博得奧林園亞歡心的
I need to know to get on Olympia's good side?
千萬別告訴委託人你的看法
Never give your opinion to a client.
讓她來說
Leave that to her.
你好 雷蒙德 喬丹
Hello, Raymond, Jordan.
我們還有另一位律師的加入
Got one more lawyer as we bring this home.
請說出你的名字
Please state your name
以及你是否跟
and whether you've ever had
警察局或我父親的案子
any affiliation with the police department
有過直接或間接的關係
or with my father's case, either directly or tangentially.
喬丹喜歡把一切錄下來
Jordan likes to record everything.
我不是喜歡錄
I don't like to record everything,
我是不得不錄
I have to record everything.
這樣才能追責
To keep people accountable.
我父親因為謊言被關了26年
My father was locked up for 26 years because people lied,
所以 如果有人在這裏撒謊
so, if it happens in this room,
我都有記錄
I have a record.
我理解
I understand.
很抱歉
Apologies.
瑪德琳·馬特洛克
Madeline Matlock.
我和警察局沒有任何關係
I have no affiliation with the police department
從來沒有過
and never have.
怎麼了
What is it?
出什麼事了
What's wrong?
他們開出了最後的和解協議
The final settlement offer came in,
是24萬1280美元
and it's $241,280,
在這個條件下 我必須問一下
and at this point I have to ask
你們要不要和解
if you want to settle.
什麼 當初200萬
What? We didn't settle
我們都沒和解
for $2 million.
你憑什麼覺得 我們會接受20萬
What the hell makes you think we'd settle for $200,000?
對不起
Sorry.
不 對不起
No, no. Sorry.
你不必道歉
You don't have to apologize.
但我不明白 究竟出什麼事了
Okay, I don't understand. What happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
庭審就在明天
But the trial starts tomorrow,
事情有了些變數
and something changed.
他們覺得我們的案子站不住腳
They don't feel like we can make our case anymore,
我很擔心
and I'm worried.
沒有確鑿的證據
Without the smoking gun,
再加上你父親之前的犯罪記錄
given your father's prior criminal history
以及他曾對罪行供認不諱
and the fact that he confessed to the crime...
我是屈打成招
Under duress.
我後來翻供了 我知道
I took it back. -I know.
但一開始的認罪 就意味著政府
But that initial confession means that the city
沒有義務付你一分一毫
is not obligated to pay you anything.
對不起 雷蒙德 我們
I'm sorry, Raymond, we've just--
我們沒時間了
we've run out of time.
所以 你現在
OLYMPIA [on recording]: So... you have
面臨一個重大決定 雷蒙德
a very big decision to make, Raymond.
還記得這個嗎 這是我們第一次會面的錄音
Remember this? This is from our first meeting.
我經常聽
I listen to it a lot.
你們已經見了很多律師
You've met with a lot of lawyers,
我很想告訴你 怎樣選都不會錯
and I'd like to say there's no wrong decision,
但你知道嗎
but you know what?
你們確實會選錯
There is a wrong decision.
但這也意味著 你們還有正確的選擇
But that also means there's a right decision.
我就是那個正確的選擇
And I am that right decision
因為我相信你 雷蒙德
because I believe in you, Raymond.
我在乎的點 在於這個腐敗的警察局
And I care that this corrupt police department
偷走了你的未來
stole your future.
相信我 相信我吧
Trust me. Trust me.
你覺得呢
What do you think?
呃
Um...
說吧
Go on.
你要是有什麼意見 就說出來
If you have an opinion, give it.
他們的和解無異於羞辱 咱們上法庭吧
Their offer's insulting. Go to trial.
我同意
I agree.
你說過你有辦法贏 找辦法吧
You said you'd come through, so come through.
你們覺得奧林園亞 會怪我勸他們庭審嗎
You think Olympia's blaming me for going to trial?
可能不會 百分百會
Probably not. A hundred percent yes.
我是說 我會的
I mean, I would.
你是說 馬特洛克女士壓你一頭
You're saying Ms. Matlock convinced them
說服了他們
and one-upped you?
她沒壓我一頭 我現在又有更多理由
She didn't one-up me. Now I'm a step closer
解雇她了
to firing her for cause.
坦白講 我也不想讓雷蒙德和解
And frankly, I didn't want to convince Raymond to settle.
不像話 律所需要你回到
Unacceptable. The firm needs you back
那些真正賺錢的案子上來
on cases that actually make money.
我連續三年的計費都超過了
And I billed more than any other junior partner
其他初級合夥人
for three straight years.
可你追了一個案子6個月都徒勞無功
Yeah, hard to remember when you've been hunting
之前的好感都敗光了
goose eggs for six months.
因為我在幫咱們
Because I'm trying to establish
開拓全新的收入源 沒一個人支持我
a whole new revenue stream with no support.
對方曾三次試圖更改庭審地點
I fought off three separate attempts
都被我擊敗了
to have the venue changed by myself,
也就是說 整個陪審團都知道
which means the whole jury pool knows that there has been
警察腐敗現象的嚴重
extensive police corruption.
陪審團之所以知道 是因為
And the whole jury pool knows that because I've
我讓這事上了報紙
kept the story in the paper.
所以 之前政府才同意和解的
Which is why the city was settling.
之前 是關鍵
"Was" being the operative word.
太對了 那時我連個私家偵探
Exactly. And without a private investigator
其至陪審團顧問都沒有
or, at the very least, a jury consultant,
現在依然沒有
I have no idea what changed.
律所不想把錢投到無償案件上
Well, the firm isn't gonna pump money into a pro bono case.
理想狀況下
Well, ideally,
這不是無償案子 這只是一個試水案件
this isn't pro bono. It's a test case.
奧林匹亞之前為大型製藥公司做辯護 搞得精疲力盡
Olympia got burned out after defending Big Pharma.
大型製藥公司 他們有錢啊 我想去
Oh, Big Pharma, big money. That's where I want to be.
對了 什麼叫試水案件
So what do you mean this is a test case?
如果雷蒙德得到的賠償金
Well, if Raymond gets a number
高於全國平均水平
higher than the national average,
律所就會從中抽成
then the firm takes a cut.
所以奧林匹亞一方面告訴他
So Olympia's argument to him is that she can get
能幫他爭取更高的金額
a much higher number.
一方面又告訴律所 追求社會正義
And the argument to the firm is that social justice
也能賺得真金白銀
can mean real money.
行善和賺錢可以兼得
So you can do good and do well.
總之 這是高尚的說法
That's the noble version, anyway.
不高尚的說法呢
What's the non-noble version?
她在尋找一種將不幸變現的方法
She's figuring out yet another way to monetize misfortune
因為她就是那麼天才
because she's a freaking genius. Mm-hmm.
你馬上要成高級合夥人了
You're coming up for senior partnership.
熟輕熟重 不需要我提醒你吧
I don't have to remind you what's at stake.
那你還提醒
Then why are you?
因為我仍舊是你公公
Because I'm still your father-in-law.
離婚手續馬上走完了
The divorce is almost finalized.
你以為我在乎嗎
You think I give a rat's ass?
公公是個終生的身份
Father-in-law is a lifetime position.
我知道熟輕熟重
I know what's at stake.
我只是希望這條路能走通
I just want this to work.
我知道
I know you do.
但如果走不通
But if it doesn't,
你還要回來做公司訴訟的
you're back on corporate litigation.
明白嗎
Got it?
現在最重要也是我們
So the biggest question
必須定下的事情
we have to tackle is:
是要讓雷蒙德出庭嗎
should Raymond be called to the stand?
要是有個陪審團顧問就好了
What we need is a jury consultant
這樣就可以提前
so that we can audition
排練一下雷蒙德的證詞
Raymond's testimony,
看看模擬陪審團會反應如何
see how the mock jury will respond to him.
但很不幸 我們請不起
But unfortunately we can't afford that.
所以 你需要的是白牌貨
So you need the off-brand model, huh?
這麼說吧 甚至是免費贈品
Or better yet, a freebie.
自從我消費降級後
Which is what I'm always looking for
我也一直在找這些東西
since my circumstances changed.
舉個例子 我已經不買番茄醬了
For instance, I stopped buying ketchup
而是把在外面吃飯的番茄醬包
and I started bringing ketchup packets home
帶回家
every time I went out.
而這家律所一定有很多人
And this firm definitely has a lot of people
喜歡番茄醬
who like ketchup.
什麼 老頭子知道我們要往下推進了
What? Senior knows we're moving forward
他才是這裏的老大
and he's the one in charge,
所以你別來插手 我是來幫忙
so give me space. I came to offer
當你副手的
my services as second chair
避免你過去的六個月
so these last six months haven't been
白忙一場 但你要是不想我插手
a colossal waste of time, but if you want space...
不 不是的
No, no, no, I don't.
抱歉 謝謝你
I'm sorry. Thank you.
對了 你能在大樓裏幫我找
Actually, can you look around the building and find me
兩個40多歲的黑人
two Black men in their 40s,
一個50多歲的拉丁裔男人
a 50-something Latino man,
一個20多歲的亞洲女性
a 20-something Asian woman,
和兩個50多歲的白人女性嗎
and two white ladies in their 50s?
你可以去秘書處
Go to the secretaries,
維修部 餐飲部找找
the maintenance department, food services...
律所已經雇了他們
They already work here.
所以 他們就是我們的免費番茄醬
So they're our free ketchup packets.
我們會根據陪審團的人口構成
We'll match the demographics
找來相應的律所員工
of the jury and preview Raymond's testimony
然後一起預演雷蒙德的證詞
with people who are already here on the clock.
你們三個 我們是可以分拆的
And you three... You know, you can actually separate us...
噓
Shh!
去謝琳家把她的素描拿過來
Go to Sherleen's and get her sketch. Hmm?
謝琳是誰 一個老妓女
Who's Sherleen? An old ho.
她就是這麼叫自己的
That's what she calls herself.
我有次稱她為 性工作長者 她還糾正我
I said "aging prostitute" once and she corrected me,
我是個老妓女 收到
"I'm an old ho."Copy that.
我只是說
I'm just saying,
馬特吉弗說了一大段的番茄醬
MacGyver does a whole ketchup monologue
都沒被她閉嘴
and she doesn't get shushed.
我叫馬特洛克
It's-it's Matlock, ha!
因為那一長段番茄醬 說到點子上了
Because the ketchup monologue was useful.
好了 別糾結了
Get over yourself.
順便交代下 謝琳是個十足的瘋貨
FYI, Sherleen's kind of a nutjob.
但她在街上工作了很久
But she's worked the streets a long time
她說她對我們
and she says that she remembers
在找的那個妓女有印象
the prostitute we're looking for.
除了不記得她名字 和任何有用的信息
Just not her name. Or anything useful.
而且 莎拉
And, Sarah... Shh.
小心眼兒
So petty.
她誰啊
Who's she?
你好 我是瑪蒂 很高興認識你
Hey, I'm Matty. It's nice to meet you.
你家真不錯哎
Wow. I love your place.
謝了 我自己佈置的
Thanks, I did the art.
那邊那個 可以很直觀的讓你有個瞭解
That over there is a useful map.
你知道陰蒂在哪裏嗎
You know where your clitoris is?
很多你這年紀的女人都不知道
Lots of women your age don't.
我是肯定知道的 可我丈夫就不知道了
I certainly do. Though my husband didn't.
而且我什麼都沒說過 想想看
And I never said anything. Imagine that.
38年我連句
38 years and I never said,
你能稍微往左一丁點
"Could you just move a little to the left
速度提一倍嗎 都沒說過
and go twice as fast?"
當然了 他也沒跟我說過
Course, he never told me he was sleeping
他跟別人睡了 還染上了嚴重賭癮
with other people and had a massive gambling problem,
搞得我欠了一身債 所以算是扯平了吧
which left me in debt, so I guess we're even.
我喜歡她
I like her.
我也喜歡你
I like you, too.
謝謝你幫我們
Thanks for helping us.
我去找下那幅素描
I'll go find the sketch.
慢慢找
Take your time.
這裏可欣賞的太多了
Wow, there's so much to look at here.
顯然你過得很充實
Clearly a life well-lived.
我就不一樣了 挑錯男人了
Not me. I picked the wrong man.
好 素描在這兒
Okay, here's my sketch.
其實是幅畫
Actually, it's a painting.
哇哦
Wow.
用了很多橙色啊
Lot of orange up top.
是她的髮色嗎 沒錯
That's her hair color? Exactly.
很混亂 對不對
It's very chaotic, isn't it?
毒品讓人混亂
Drugs make people chaotic.
確實
They certainly do.
你們有查過 一年內
And you all ran the names
被謝琳畫過的
of all the prostitutes arrested
所有妓女的名字嗎
within the year by Sherleen?
當然了 整個蘭州地區的都查了
Of course. In the whole tristate area.
很好 查過跟有跟毒品相關
Nice. And, uh, you looked for people
指控的人嗎
with narcotics charges?
畢竟根據這副素描所示 我們這位
Since our, uh, our prostitute here had
妓女有 混亂的毒品問題
a "chaotic" drug problem, per this sketch?
沒有
We... did not.
可能範圍太大了
Well, that's probably too big a pool.
謝琳
Sherleen,
這些妓女有常光顧的毒販嗎
was there a drug dealer the other hos favored?
你好呀
Hello there.
模擬陪審團怎麼樣
How'd the mock jury go?
很有用
Useful.
但不幸的是 他們對雷蒙德證詞的
But, unfortunately, we got a pretty mixed reaction
反應不一 所以我不能讓他上庭
to Raymond's testimony, so I cannot put him on the stand.
他女兒得幫我們爭取同情票了
His daughter's gonna have to get those sympathy votes for us,
可她不是很樂意
which she is not excited about.
有個好消息
Well, you're gonna like this.
我們可能拿到失蹤妓女的線索了
We might have a lead on our missing prostitute.
謝琳記得有個叫 大維尼的
Sherleen remembered a guy named Big Vinnie
曾經給所有女生供貨
who used to supply all the girls,
所以我們查了一下
so we did a little digging,
他的真名叫文森特·德盧卡
and his real name is Vincent De Luca.
現在在伊文戴爾監獄 我們打算
In prison at Evandale. We're gonna go up
明早過去
in the morning.
好
Okay.
終於有好消息了
Some good news... finally.
問題是
Uh, the thing is,
線索是我發現的
I'm the one who figured that out. Mm.
我希望你覺得我是個可用之人
And I'm hoping you're finding me useful
因為 我想了一下
because... I've thought about it
我真的不想捲進你跟
and I really don't think it's a good idea for me
朱利安的監護權糾紛
to get involved in your custody dispute with Julian.
特別是感恩節到了
Over Thanksgiving.
好 沒問題
Okay, no problem.
太好了
Great.
我之所以丟給你 是因為你之前
I only asked because you wanted to know
想不遺餘力討我歡心
how to get on my good side.
你好 朱利安 嘿
Hey there, Julian. Hey.
我來問下皮博迪的情況
I'm just checking in on Peabody.
成交價2300萬
Closed at $23 million,
就像你說的
just like you said.
今晚我得帶孩子
I've got the kids tonight,
不然咱們能一起喝杯蘇威
otherwise we'd be having a Scotch.
不了 我不喝威士忌
Oh, well, no Scotch for me...
除非要跟別人上床
Mm. ...unless I'm getting laid.
我想這應該不會發生
Mm. I guess... I guess that's not on the table.
你是怎麼到這兒的啊 瑪德琳·馬特洛克
Where did you come from, Madeline Matlock?
最開始是佛羅里達的那不勒斯
Naples, Florida, originally,
後來去佐治亞繞了一圈
then a little detour through Georgia
再被我前夫拖去了北方
before my ex-husband dragged me up north.
不是說因此 我才變得很苦很窮
Not that I'm bitter and broke.
你是專門
You specialize
打藥品官司的 對吧
in pharmaceuticals, right?
我也想往這方面發展
Mm-hmm. That's where I need to be.
你孩子們多大了
How old are your kids?
雙胞胎 都是八歲
Uh, twins. They're eight.
正是好年紀 是啊
Aw. That's a great age. Yeah.
12歲就難帶了 我現在在帶我孫子
12 is tougher. I'm raising my grandson...
別找我問建議
but don't ask me for any advice--
他可討厭我了
he loathes me.
你感恩節週末有什麼安排嗎
Have you got any plans for Thanksgiving weekend?
奧林匹亞說
Because Olympia mentioned
她想帶雙胞胎出去玩玩
she'd love to take the twins on a little getaway.
當然是你們共進晚餐之後了
After you all have dinner together, of course.
而且放個假 對大家都有好處
And vacations do benefit everyone.
奧林園亞讓你來的 管我要週末陪護權
Did Olympia send you? To ask for my weekend?
然後朱利安解釋說
And so then Julian explained that he'd be
如果你願意一個月內搬出婚房
more than happy to let you have his weekend
並把房契轉讓給他
if you leave the marital apartment
他很樂意讓你那個週末
within the month and cede the deed to him
帶孩子 那麼 成交不
in pleno. So? Do we have a deal?
荒唐 你根本沒安排
You're being ridiculous. You don't have plans.
我還真有哦
Oh, as a matter of fact, I do.
我荒唐
And I'm the one being ridiculous?
不好意思 能讓我倆單獨談談嗎
I'm sorry. Uh, will you excuse us?
沒問題
Oh, you bet.
荒唐的是 你竟然派馬特洛克幫你於這種骯髒事
Ridiculous is sending Matlock to do your dirty work.
我想著 她也許能說服你
I thought she'd have more luck.
看你還挺喜歡她的
You seemed to like her in the meeting.
你生氣是因為我在會上打壓你
You're pissed because I undercut you in the meeting.
是因為你針對我
Yeah, because it was personal.
才不是 我只是覺得你
That's not true. I don't think you're acting
沒為律所著想
in the firm's best interests.
你大可以發郵件給我啊 而不是
Well, you could have emailed me rather than going
當眾針對我 是
after me in public. Yeah...
不好意思 打斷一下 有麻煩了
Sorry to interrupt, but we have a problem.
看下《郵報》
Check the Post.
哈里斯案即將開庭之際 一項研究顯示
"On the eve of the Harris trial, a study reveals
90年代末的警察腐敗現象
"police corruption in the late '90s
並不像最初報道的那樣普遍
not as widespread as initially reported"?
什麼 而且不僅僅是《郵報》
What? -And it's not just the Post.
其他媒體也在跟進
All the other outlets are picking it up.
好吧 呃
Okay, um...
你可以走了 我們稍後再談
You could go, we'll talk later.
我哪兒都不去
I'm not going anywhere.
制定下策略吧
Let's strategize.
為了律所利益
For the good of the firm?
警察工會肯定知道
Policemen's union must have known
會發這篇文章
this article was coming out,
所以他們才降價了 沒錯
and that's why they dropped the number. Yeah.
顯然是他們精心策劃的
They orchestrated this, clearly.
特意趕在開庭前一晚 放出這篇文章
And held on to the article for the night before the trial
目的就是盡最大可能 影響陪審團
so they could inflict the most prejudice on the jury.
我整個案件都基於
My entire case is based
警察腐敗
on police corruption.
該死 希望你那個毒販
Damn it! Let's hope your dealer remembers
還能記得26年前 那個吸毒的妓女
a drug-addicted prostitute from 26 years ago.
你有計劃嗎
You have a plan?
讓他張嘴說話
To get him to talk to you?
當然有
We sure do.
我們有計劃嗎 還沒有
Do we have a plan? Not yet.
但我們有一整晚時間想辦法
We've got all night to come up with something.
記住 霍博肯 布倫達
Now remember, Hoboken, Brenda,
弗羅裏達的第一浸信會教堂
First Baptist Church, Florida.
研究的特別到位 莎拉
Excellent research, Sarah.
相當棒
Really top-notch.
我不認識
Uh, I don't know
這些人 文森特·德盧卡
these people. Vincent De Luca,
回頭我跟你媽告狀去
I'm gonna tell your mother you said that.
你認識我媽
You know my mom?
是我呀 瑪蒂
It's me. Matty.
我搬去霍博肯的時候
I met your mom when I moved
認識的你媽
up north to Hoboken.
開托兒所
Ran day care.
第一浸信會 跟你布倫達姑姑一起辦的
First Baptist? With your Aunt Brenda?
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我一激動就會
My emphysema flares up
肺氣腫發作
when I, when I get upset.
不怪你
It's not your fault.
只是我生病之後
I guess I just look different
變化很大
since I got sick.
瘦了很多
Lost a lot of weight.
我只是沒想到 你竟然認不出我
I just never thought you wouldn't recognize me.
不是 只是需要點時間想一下
No, it just took a second.
我認出你了
I-I recognize you.
我剛開玩笑的 謝天謝地
I was just kidding around. -Thank God.
我剛還突然緊張了一下 以為自己會在這些
'Cause I suddenly panicked that I'd look nuts
律師面前 看起來像個瘋婆子
in front of these lawyers.
他們去家裏那邊
They came to the neighborhood
找你媽
looking for your mom,
我跟他們說 辛迪搬去佛羅里達了
and I told them, "Cindy moved to Florida.
有什麼事呀 然後我們就來這兒了
And how can I help?" And here we are.
他們今天好像有個大案子要開庭
I think they got some big trial starting today.
首先 鑒於昨晚發佈的那篇
First, I'll make a motion in limine
帶有偏見的文章
to try to get the location moved...
我會提出建議
In light of the highly prejudicial article
改變庭審地點 兩個月前 你還說
that came out last night. Two months ago, you argued
陪審團能應對這些報道呢
the jury could handle the publicity.
不可能成功 但我們得把這事記錄在案 以備上訴用
It won't work, but we need it on record for appeal.
開庭時 駁回陪審團坐定後
Motion denied. After the jury is seated,
會進入到開庭陳詞
we'll move into opening arguments.
那是我第一次講述你故事的機會
That's my first chance to tell your story.
這是個恐怖故事
And it's a horror story.
雷蒙德·哈里斯在方寸牢籠裏
Raymond Harris spent 26 years
待了26年 明知自己是無辜的
in a six-by-nine cell, knowing he was innocent
但也知道
but also knowing
無人在意
that no one cared.
但你們可以讓他知道 你們在乎
But you can show him that you care.
那時我會解釋
And that's when I'll try to get in
你不出庭作證的原因
an explanation for the reason you're not taking the stand.
你們可以讓他知道 你們關心他的創傷
You can show him that you care about his trauma.
到現在他還無法入睡
The fact that he still can't sleep.
害怕在公眾面前說話
He has a crippling fear of public speaking.
反對 反對我開庭陳詞
Objection. During my opening statement?
上前說話
Approach the bench.
她顯然是在暗示她的委託人
She's clearly trying to imply that her client
之所以沒出庭 是因為受到了精神創傷
isn't testifying because he's been traumatized,
我們都知道 真實原因是
when we know for a fact that it's because
她不希望他前科被拎出來講
she doesn't want his priors brought up.
這次我還是
Again,
會失敗
I'll lose,
但我得讓陪審團記住這點
but we'll get it in the jury's heads.
抱歉 法官大人
Apologies, Your Honor.
我會更加小心用詞的
I will be more careful.
26年前 一個吸毒的妓女
Look, there's just no way that I'm gonna remember a...
我怎麼可能記得住
lady-of-the-night junkie from 26 years ago.
我懂腦子
Oh, I know how tricky
有多難記事
memory can be.
我把美國老年人協會建議的
And I do all those exercises
所有練習都做過
that the AARP suggests,
可我發現 所有能觸發記憶的 往往都是具體細節
but I find what triggers my memory are specifics.
你有什麼具體細節嗎 馬丁內斯先生
You got any, Mr. Martinez?
當然有
Yeah, of course.
有些事 也許能幫你回憶起1996年的事
Here's what we can tell you to help you recall 1996.
那年是選舉年 克林頓第二個任期
It was an election year. Clinton's second term.
對手是鮑勃·多爾
Bob Dole was his opponent.
出現了第一個被克隆的哺乳動物綿羊 多莉
Dolly the sheep was the first mammal to be cloned.
那可是大事
That was a big deal.
還有麥卡雷納舞
Macarena.
所有人都在跳麥卡雷納舞
Everyone was doing the Macarena.
我可沒跳 其他人跳
I wasn't doing the Macarena. Other people were,
但我記得 當時有想過 幸好我不配槍
and I remember thinking it's a good thing I don't carry,
要不然我真會把他們腦袋崩了的
'cause I would've blown their brains out.
研究的很到位
That's great research.
但是維尼 我想你回想一下
But, Vinnie, I want you to cast your mind back
麥卡雷納搞得你很生氣的那段時光
to the time when the Macarena was making you angry.
好吧 我記得有個紅頭髮的癮君子
Okay, look, I do remember this one redhead junkie
有天突然就消失了
who just up and disappeared one day.
可能就是她
And that could be her.
不是卡拉 知道了
Not Carla. -Got it,
你記得她叫什麼嗎 不是 我當初就
but do you remember her name? No, that's what
這麼叫她的 不是卡拉
I used to called her: "Not Carla."
那會兒我很喜歡電視劇《乾杯酒吧》
See, I used to love the TV show Cheers.
你還記得那部劇嗎
Do you remember that show?
記得 但這些年輕人應該不知道
I do, but I'm guessing these kids don't.
是 也許吧
Yeah, probably not.
反正 每次我一說 乾杯卡拉
Anyway, I'd say "Cheers, Carla,"
她就會很生氣 說她不叫卡拉
and she'd get all pissed off and say that's not her name.
隨便啦 反正也差不多
Whatever, it was close.
最後我就叫她 不是卡拉
Eventually, I just called her Not Carla.
但跟卡拉很接近 對吧 卡莉 卡羅琳 卡羅萊娜
But it's like Carla, right? Carly? Caroline? Carolina?
卡爾琳娜 卡洛塔 卡琳
Carlina, Carlotta, Carlin...
卡琳 是了
Carlin. Yes.
好 駕照是1993到1998年間
Okay, driver's license 1993 to 1998,
名字是卡琳 拼寫是 卡 王 雙 木 林
first name Carlin, spelled I-N, E-N, O-N, Y-N,
年齡18到32歲之間
ages 18 to 32.
那就廣撒網吧
Might as well cast a wide net.
是 可這範圍是真的大
Yeah, well, that's very wide.
可能要花太多時間
I mean, that might take too long...
好 214個結果
Okay. 214 hits.
現在速度快多了 瑪蒂
Things are faster now, Matty.
比利 把他們生活拼湊起來
Billy, let's piece together their lives.
排除所有1996年不在本州的人
Eliminate anyone who was out of state in 1996.
要找紅頭髮
We are looking for redheads, people.
福格森警探
Detective Ferguson,
雷蒙德·哈里斯跟你和你同事們說過多少次
how many times did Raymond Harris tell you
他是無辜的
and your fellow officers that he was innocent?
不清楚
I have no idea.
給個大概數值 能有超過100次嗎
Approximately. More than 100?
反對 自問自答
Objection. Asked and answered.
法官大人 我想建立行為模式
Your Honor, I'm trying to establish a course of conduct.
允許
I'll allow it.
謝謝你認為
Thank you. Is it your best estimate
他自稱無罪的次數 超過100次了嗎
that he said he was not guilty more than 100 times?
也許吧 好的
Probably. Okay.
所以 雷蒙德·哈里斯說過一百多次 他是無罪的
So, more than 100 times Mr. Harris says he's not guilty,
但在你審問他11個小時候
and after you question him for 11 hours,
他說自己有罪了
he says he's guilty.
雷蒙德認罪多久後
How long after Raymond confessed
翻供的
did he retract that confession?
大概十分鐘後吧
About ten minutes later.
八分鐘 這期間他做了什麼
Eight. What did he do in between?
記不清了
I can't remember.
他去洗手間了
He went to the bathroom.
福格森警探 雷蒙德撤回
Detective Ferguson, after Raymond
認罪供詞後 你們做進一步調查了嗎
retracted his confession, did you investigate further?
沒有 除了被一位承認自己
No. Was there anything to link Mr. Harris
醉酒的目擊者 看到他出現在案發現場之外
to the crime scene other than the fact
還有其他任何能將哈里斯和
that he was seen in the area by one eyewitness
案發現場聯繫起來的證據嗎 有的
who was admittedly intoxicated? Yeah.
他符合我們做出的兇手描述
He matched the description we put out.
沒錯 這描述我也有
Right. I have that description.
將此作為原告證物 4B
Admitting this in evidence as plaintiff exhibit 4B.
能大聲讀一下嗎
Can you read it aloud, please?
黑人男性 無面部鬍鬚
Black male, no facial hair.
身高在五英尺十到六英尺之間
Five-foot-ten to six-foot.
當然
Well...
我能理解你為什麼會認為
I can see why you thought
是雷蒙德·哈里斯
it was Raymond Harris.
沒有更多問題了 法官大人
No more questions, Your Honor.
再次感謝你為國效力
Thank you again for your service.
我們從最後一點開始吧 福格森警探
Let's start at that last point, Detective Ferguson.
為什麼哈里斯撤回認罪後
Why didn't you investigate further
你沒有做進一步調查
after Mr. Harris retracted his confession?
因為撤回認罪很常見
Because people take back confessions all the time.
我們沒繼續調查的原因很簡單
The reason we didn't keep looking is simple:
最可信的解釋 通常就是
the most believable explanation for what happened
事情的真相
is usually what happened.
所以 在你看來
So, in your opinion this wasn't a case
本案與泛溢的警察腐敗現象無關
of widespread police corruption?
拜託 你沒看今天報紙嗎
Come on. You see the papers today?
才沒什麼氾濫的腐敗現象
There was no widespread corruption.
他們找到那個妓女了
They found the prostitute.
我已經好久都沒想起那個晚上了
Look, I haven't thought about that night for a long time.
我知道我就要死了
I knew I was going to be murdered,
也知道沒人會在意
and I knew no one would care.
所以我拚命反抗
And so I just fought.
因為上帝或者其他 你信仰的上蒼之力
And because of God or whatever higher power you believe in,
我逃出來了
I got away.
其實本來逃不出來的
And I shouldn't have.
於是我改變了自己的生活
And so I changed my life.
戒毒了
I got sober.
那是我做過最難的事
Which was the hardest thing I ever did.
但我做到了
But I did it.
後來我上了大學
And I went to college and...
過上了從沒想過的生活
I have a life that I never imagined.
但我家人不知道我的過去
But, uh, my family doesn't know about my past.
我老公不知道孩子們 也不知道
Not my husband, not my kids.
你可以在非公開法庭上作證
Well, you could testify in closed court.
我們只需要證明你在雷蒙德
We just need to establish that you reported
入獄期間 報告過被人攻擊
the attack while Raymond was in jail
能證明有人掩蓋真相就行
to prove there was a cover-up.
不 會被曝出去的
No, it will get out.
我孩子才十幾歲
I have teenagers.
抱歉 我不能去
I'm sorry, I-I, I can't.
我們可以給你發傳票的
We can subpoena you.
不要 你們不明白
No. No, you don't understand,
那會毀了我家庭的
that will destroy my family.
求你們了
Please.
求求 你不知道我經歷過什麼
Please, you don't know what I've been through.
其實我們不能傳喚你的
We can't actually subpoena you.
在這個階段
To get you added
把你加入證人名單
to the witness list this late,
我們得提交一份
we'd have to submit an affidavit
你願意合作的宣誓書
with your cooperation.
我不會合作的
Well, I won't give it.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不能騙她
I couldn't lie to her.
你也不用明確告知她
Well, you also didn't have to give her
如何逃避作證嗎
the road map on how to get out of testifying.
你說得對 我太久沒上班了
You're right. And i-it's been a while,
所以 也許 也許什麼
so maybe... Maybe what?
也許 你不該回來上班
Maybe you shouldn't have come back to work?
我同意
I agree.
所以在你提出區別對待和
Which is why I didn't want you hired from the moment
年齡歧視的那一刻 我就不想雇你
you brought up discriminatory practices and ageism,
你那就是濫用法律武器
which is an offensive manipulation of a law
而那條法律 主要是為了防止從業者
that was established primarily to keep workers from getting
被提前趕出公司 而你被拒絕的原因
pushed out prematurely, whereas you getting blocked
則是因為你已經30年
was likely because it has been 30 years
沒有從事法律工作了
since you've practiced law.
從最好的情況來看
Which, best-case scenario,
你剛證明了這條法律的災難程度
you just proved to be a recipe for disaster.
至於最壞的情況
Worst-case scenario?
你給了那女人一條出路
You gave that woman a way out
就因為你同情她
because you felt sorry for her.
因為你看到她
Because you saw her
住在郊區
living in suburbia
讓你想起了你自己
and she reminded you of yourself.
但你知道嗎 那些讓你有共鳴的人
But you know what? Those people who remind you
相比於那些讓我有共鳴的人
of yourself have generations of advantage
享受了太多代的優勢了
over the people who remind me of myself.
你知道誰讓我想起自己了嗎
Do you know who I identify with?
雷蒙德和他的家人
Raymond and his family.
而你剛剛把他們搞砸了
Who you just screwed over.
嘿 阿爾菲 是奶奶啊
Hey, Alfie, it's Grammy.
抱歉啊 我又不能回家吃晚飯了
Oh, I'm so sorry I won't be home for dinner again.
我聽起來怪怪的
I sound weird?
沒有啦 我沒事
No, I'm fine.
只是很忙
Just busy.
有人叫我晚點再跟你聊哈
I'm getting called in, so I'll talk to you later.
想吃點咸的嗎
Something salty?
我不太會給人打氣
I'm not one for pep talks,
但我是來支持
but I am here to support
比利要給你的一些建議
whatever Billy is about to say to you.
不用說
There's no need to say it.
我錯了 太感情用事了
I was wrong, I let my emotions get in the way.
我年輕的時候絕不會這樣
Something I'd never do when I was younger.
那時候我把事情分的很清楚
Back then I kept things separate.
我只是不能
I just can't...
讓更多人失望了
I can't let any more people down.
尤其是在我人生這個階段 我只是
Not at this moment in my life, I just...
做不到
Can't do it.
好吧 呃
Okay. Um...
是時候克服自我了
Time to get over yourself.
這很正常
This is completely normal.
大家都跑天台來哭 還記得嗎
You know, we're on the crying patio, remember?
但拜託
But come on.
我們跟你一起取得的成就
I mean, we've accomplished more with you
比這一年加起來都多
than we have all year.
倒也不是啦
I mean, that's not entirely true.
怎麼了 誇大其詞並不會讓人好受呀
What? Hyperbole helps no one.
但顯而易見 你還派的上用場
But you've obviously been useful.
所以
So...
別再自怨自艾了 振作起來
stop feeling bad for yourself and pull up whatever
把這事解決掉
granny panties you wear and fix it.
好嗎
Okay?
喬丹 你父親
Jordan, after your father
被錯判入後 你生活發生了什麼變化
was wrongfully imprisoned, how did your life change?
我們沒了房子 我不得不轉學
Well, we lost our housing. I had to switch schools.
所有人都知道我父親
And everybody knew that my father
被判強姦和謀殺罪
was convicted of rape and murder,
所以你猜 誰想跟我一起玩
so you know who wanted to hang around me?
那些覺得這種事很酷的人
Hmm? People who thought that was cool.
怎麼會影響到你呢
And how did that affect you?
怎麼會影響不到呢
I mean, how didn't it affect me?
能說得再具體些嗎
Can you be more specific?
這是你的機會 喬丹
This is your chance, Jordan.
我現在37歲
Well, I'm 37 years old now and...
從沒談過戀愛
I've never had a relationship.
為什麼 因為
Why? Because
如果我認為我父親做出過
if I thought my father was capable
這種可怕的事 那我怎麼可能
of this terrible thing, then how could I trust
信任別人
anyone?
但其實 他並沒有做
But he wasn't capable of it.
沒事的 有事
It's okay. No.
有事
It's not okay.
因為最糟糕的是
Because the worst part is,
最糟糕的是我和我爸
the worst part is that me and my dad,
我們曾經很親密 而我
we used to be close, and I...
我不知道 怎樣才能找回那樣的時光
I don't know how to get that back.
我找不回來了
I can't get that back.
沒有其他問題了 法官大人
No further questions, Your Honor.
就五分鐘
Just five minutes.
拜託了
Please.
我昨天幫了你
I helped you yesterday.
聽著 我知道這很重要
Look, I understand what's at stake.
我也理解你為什麼拒絕
And I understand why you said no.
比你想像的更理解
More than you know.
我有過一個女兒
I had a daughter.
在與毒品長期鬥爭後 她去世了
And she died after a long battle with drugs.
我每天都承受著失去她的痛苦
And I carry the weight of that loss every day.
通常我都能承受 對吧
And usually I can handle it, right?
但是
But...
有時 它總是出乎意料地
...once in a while, and it's always unexpected...
成為我唯一能看見的東西
...it becomes the only thing in the room.
昨天又發生了這樣的事
And yesterday that's what happened.
當你談到
When you were talking about
你如何努力戒掉毒癮
how hard you worked to get clean
以及你已經取得了多大的進步時候
and how far you'd come...
我想到了 我該為我的女兒做些什麼
...I thought about what I'd do for my daughter.
答案是 我願意做任何事
And the answer is anything.
我願傾盡一切
Everything.
但這事關雷蒙德·哈里斯和他的家人
But this is about Raymond Harris and his family.
他們已經被毀了
And they've been destroyed.
但是 我不想毀了我的生活
But I don't want to blow up my life.
再說也不能保證他們就會相信我
Plus there's no guarantee they'll even believe me.
我是說 人們是不會關心妓女的
I mean, people don't care about prostitutes.
即使在那時 我也知道這是不會有結果的
Even back then I knew it would go nowhere.
這就是為什麼我沒有
That's why I didn't...
什麼
What?
卡琳 我以
Carlin, I promise you
我女兒的名義 向你保證
on my daughter's memory...
我不會背叛你
...I will not betray you.
但我需要知道 你都知道些什麼
But I need to know what you know.
這家希臘餐館的老闆看到
The owner of this Greek restaurant
我把那傢伙打退了
saw me fight the guy off.
然後他陪我去了警察局
And he walked me to the police station.
你好
Hi there.
我想知道克裏斯多老爹 還是這家店的老闆嗎
I'm wondering if Papa Cristo still owns this establishment?
首先 我想說我很理解
First, I want to say I appreciate
有個坐牢的父親 對你來說有多難
how hard it must have been having a father in jail.
雖然你之前經歷過他進監獄
Though you had experienced his incarceration before,
對吧 在你還小的時候
am I right? Earlier in life?
反對 我們能上前嗎
Objection! Can we approach?
這顯然帶有偏見
That was clearly prejudicial.
和暗示你的當事人 不出庭作證
As prejudicial as suggesting your client
是因為他害怕公開演講一樣有偏見嗎 比那更糟
isn't testifying because he's afraid of public speaking? Worse.
他讓陪審團把我的當事人
He just made sure that the jury sees
當成罪犯 而不是受害者
my client as a criminal instead of a victim.
夠了
Enough!
反對有效 下次再發生這種事
Objection sustained, and the next time this happens,
你倆都會面臨著無效審判
you're both looking at a mistrial.
所以 我去了克裏斯多老爹餐廳
And so I went to Papa Cristo's restaurant,
信不信由你 他還在那裏
and believe it or not, he's still there,
頭腦還和以前一樣靈敏 而且他比我年紀都大
still sharp as a tack, and he's older than me.
這太荒謬了
This is ridiculous.
案子都到這個階段了
You cannot introduce a new witness
你不能再加新證人進來
this late in the case.
更不用說 沒有妓女本人
Not to mention, without the prostitute,
這不過是26年前的傳聞
it's hearsay from 26 years ago.
這可以算是激情表述
Which qualifies as an excited utterance.
克裏斯多老爹告訴她 他目睹襲擊時
Papa Cristo told her he was on the phone
正在打電話
when he witnessed the attack.
那又怎樣 他真的喊出看到的一切了嗎
So what? He screamed to a friend?
得了
Come on.
誰能清楚地為26年前的
How can anyone testify with clarity
一段對話作證呢
to a conversation that happened 26 years ago?
啊 我明白了 但我問一下
Ah. I got it. But just so I know
以防萬一
for the future,
如果那朋友錄下了電話內容 可以嗎
if the friend taped the call, that'd be okay?
都這麼晚了
I mean, you wouldn't argue
你不會那個時候才反對 承認錄音的存在吧
against admitting the tape this late?
那個朋友錄下了通話嗎
Did a friend tape the call?
不 但假設的話
No. But hypothetically.
假設那朋友錄下了電話
Hypothetically, if a friend taped the call,
我們會承認的
we'd admit it.
明白了 嗯 事情是這樣的
Gotcha. Well, here's the thing--
克裏斯多老爹 沒有給朋友打電話
Papa Cristo didn't call a friend.
他報了警
He called 911.
所以 我們申請了錄音
So we requested the audio recording,
錄音不在警察局
which wasn't at the police station,
但幸運的是 在州服務器上有通話備份
but luckily it was backed up on the state's server,
所以
so...
我們要把它作為證據嗎
we'll go ahead and admit that into evidence?
帶著你的祝福呈上
With your blessing.
是的 嘿 我剛看到一個女孩 從一個傢伙的車裏逃出來
PAPA CRISTO [on recording]: Yeah, hey, I just saw some girl escape this guy's car.
等一下 親愛的 我在報警呢
Hang on, honey, I'm on with 911!
她脖子上圍著長筒襪什麼的 然後
She's got like a stocking or something around her neck and...
噢 她說她沒事
Oh, she says she's okay,
但我還是要送她去警局
but I'm gonna walk her down to the station, though.
弗格森警探
Detective Ferguson,
根據你的經驗
using your metrics,
以最可信的情況來說
what is the most believable scenario
為什麼這個電話 沒有記錄在你的轄區呢
for why this call was not logged in your precinct?
是有人把記錄刪掉了
Someone got rid of the record.
意思是 有人為了給我的委託人定罪
Meaning they buried the evidence
而隱藏了證據
in order to convict my client?
是的
Yeah.
陪審團作出一致裁決了嗎
Has the jury reached a verdict?
是的 法官大人
Yes, we have, Your Honor.
紐約州對雷蒙德·哈里斯有補償義務嗎
Does the State of New York owe a duty to Raymond Harris?
答案是肯定的
The answer is yes.
請說明 你們認定的應當
Please state the total amount of money
賠償原告雷蒙德·哈里斯的總金額
that you would compensate the plaintiff Raymond Harris.
2000萬美元
$20 million.
你剛才說的那些
What you said up there--
我們要重建我們的關係
we're gonna build back our relationship.
我愛你
I love you.
很抱歉
I'm sorry
我之前忽略了客戶的最大利益
for losing sight of the client's best interest.
這種情況不會再發生了
Won't happen again.
我希望你能支持我 爭取永久職位
And I hope you'll support my bid for permanent employment.
你給我爭取來感恩節週末了嗎
Did you get me Thanksgiving weekend?
沒有
No.
但話說回來 我猜你不想要那個週末
But then again, I'm guessing you didn't want the weekend.
因為如果你想要
Because if you did,
你就不會引導你前夫離開了
you wouldn't have baited your ex-husband into going away.
就像你一開始引導
Same way you baited me
我對這個案子發表的意見一樣
into giving my opinion on the case early on.
所以 我想知道你為什麼想讓他離開紐約
Which makes me wonder why you want him out of the city.
但也許我想多了
But maybe I'm overthinking.
也許不是因為你在和別人約會
Maybe it's not that you're dating someone new,
某個他不喜歡的人
someone he'd be unhappy about.
也許只是我想多了
That's just where my paranoid mind went.
嗯
Hmm.
你的推薦信通過審查了
Your references checked out
你很有幫助
and you were useful,
所以給你分配了
so you've been assigned
一間辦公室
an office.
我期待著再次與你合作
And I look forward to working with you again.
請把它關掉
Please turn that off.
不行
No way.
我要看幾集 安吉拉·蘭斯伯裏
I'm gonna watch a few episodes, Angela Lansbury.
等我們喝完酒看 是嗎
After we drink, right?
你來嗎 瑪蒂
You coming, Matty?
哦 要是我再年輕40歲
Oh, if only I was 40 years younger
而且家裏沒有一個搗亂的孫子就好了
and didn't have a surly grandson at home.
明天見
I'll see you two tomorrow.
我得去趕公交了
I got to catch my bus.
好吧 晚安
All right, good night.
就一站嗎 對
Just the one stop? Just the one.
晚上好 馬庫斯
Good evening, Marcus.
晚上好 金斯頓夫人
Good evening, Mrs. Kingston.
嗯 你看當女人變老時
Well, you see there's this funny thing
會發生一件有趣的事情
that happens when women age.
我們變得近乎隱形
We become damn near invisible.
沒人會警惕我們的存在
Nobody sees us coming.
人生中總有那麼一段時間
There's a time in life when you make decisions
你會根據自己的想法做決定
based on what you think is right.
但現在我又窮又困頓
But now I'm bitter and broke.
她來了 我們的征戰大將軍
There she is. Our conquering hero.
如果你知道 我在工作時是怎麼說你的
Well, you'd been a lot less cheery if you knew
你就不會這麼高興了
how I talked about you at work.
賭博 出軌
Gambling, cheating...
還說你死了 嗯
not to mention dead. Well,
瑪德琳·馬特洛克可以褻瀆關於我的假記憶
Madeline Matlock can desecrate my false memory
只要瑪德琳·金斯頓還愛我就行
as long as Madeline Kingston loves me.
我愛你 嗯
I do. Aw.
如果再讓我吃一個這玩意兒
And if I have to eat one more of these,
我就要殺人了
I'm gonna kill somebody.
但無辜的老太太是真喜歡買 姥姥
But they really sell harmless old lady. -Grammy!
阿爾菲
Oh! Alfie.
親愛的
Oh, sweetheart, oh...
我在帶孫子
I'm raising my grandson.
不用向我徵求任何意見 他討厭我
Don't ask me for any advice. He loathes me.
看到了嗎 你昨晚白擔心了一場
See? You were upset for nothing last night.
你贏了
You won.
嗯 是奧林匹亞贏了
Well, Olympia won.
我已經十年沒做律師了
I haven't practiced law in ten years.
至少我沒有毀了這案子
At least I didn't ruin it.
就像《馬特洛克》的情節一樣
It's just like on Matlock.
他們差點就輸了 但後來又贏了
They almost lose, but then they win.
我說的對嗎 你說得對
Was I right? You were right.
完美的名字嗎
Perfect name?
很適合瑪蒂 讓我們想起了媽媽
Fits with Matty, reminds us of Mom.
我能清楚地想起她 死死地盯著電視
I can see her clear as day, glued to the television,
跟大家說 她在學做律師
telling everybody she was learning
就像她媽媽一樣
to be a lawyer, just like her mother.
我想你得到那份工作了吧
I assume you got the job?
因為我創建的那個領英賬號 有大量的瀏覽
Because there's been traffic to the LinkedIn I made,
而且我把人力資源背景調查 轉給了姥爺
plus I rerouted an HR reference check to Pops.
我推薦信寫得很公允
Now, I was fair if extremely partial.
是的 我正式成為了
Yes, I'm officially a new employee
雅各布森·摩爾公司的新員工
of Jacobson Moore.
那你什麼時候 代理處理藥品案件
So, when do you get to work on drug cases?
你專攻製藥方面 對嗎
You specialize in pharmaceuticals, right?
那才是我該去的地方
That's where I need to be.
我得先建立一點信任
Well, I have to build up a little trust first.
聽著 我要做些筆記
Listen, I'm gonna make a few notes,
你去洗洗準備吃飯吧 好嗎 阿爾菲
so why don't you go get washed up for dinner, okay, Alfie?
親愛的 你看起來很累
You look tired, darling.
你確定你可以嗎
Are you sure you can do this?
我必須可以 埃德溫
I have to, Edwin.
這三人中有一人隱藏了
One of those three hid documents
可以早十年將阿片類藥物
that could have taken opioids off the market
撤出市場的文件
ten years earlier.
想想那會挽救多少生命
Think of how many lives that could have saved.
包括我們的女兒
Including our daughter's.
我想過 我該為我女兒做些什麼
I thought about what I'd do for my daughter.
答案是 我願意做任何事
And the answer is anything.
我願傾盡一切
Everything.
聽以我要查出 是誰在什麼時候 知道了什麼
So I'm gonna figure out who knew what, when.
然後呢
And then?
我要把那人送進監獄
I'm gonna put them in jail.